https://golf-direct.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy – Golf Direct – the nation's favourite discounted online golf store
Basket
No products in the basket.
QUICK Checkout
Search for:
Basket
/
£0.00
Basket
No products in the basket.
Junior Golf Bags
Junior Golf Info.
All Practice Equipment
Eyeline Golf (Practice Equipment)
Golf Mats (Practice Equipment)
Grip Trainers (Practice Equipment)
Swing Trainers (Practice Equipment)
Footjoy
Our Brands….
Nike
Our Brands….
Skycaddie
Our Brands…..
Clothing Clearance
Search for:
Privacy Policy
Golf Direct Online Ltd is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.
This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting our websites you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.
For the purpose of the European Data Protection Regulations (‘GDPR’) and the Data Protection Act 2018 (the Act) and, the data controller is Golf Direct Online Ltd, Cleveland House 116 Cleveland Street, Birkenhead, Wirral
This Privacy Statement explains how we process your information and your rights under both DPA and GDPR.
Information you give us
full name
address (and previous addresses)
date of birth
contact numbers, and
email address.
Information we collect about you
When you apply for the hire of goods, we get information about you from credit reference agencies before we can procced with your order. This is covered in more detail in the section, Who we share your information with and why.
Cookies
Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our Cookie Policy below.
Uses made of the information
Reasons/purposes for processing information
We process personal information to enable us to promote our goods and services, to maintain our accounts and records and to support and manage our staff.
Type/classes of information processed
We process information relevant to the above reasons/purposes. This may include:
personal details
family, lifestyle and social circumstances
financial details
employment and education details
goods or services provided
We also process sensitive classes of information that may include:
physical or mental health details
racial or ethnic origin
religious or other beliefs of a similar nature
trade union membership
Information you give to us. We process personal information to enable us to promote our goods and services, to maintain our accounts and records and to support and manage our staff.
Information we collect about you When you apply for credit with us we will make searches about you with credit reference agencies. We do this to make sure customers are able to manage the level of credit offered and not committing fraud by providing false or inaccurate information.
Information we receive from other sources. We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may us this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).
Data Protection says that we are allowed to use and share your personal data only where we have a proper reason to do so. The law says we must have one or more of these reasons and these are:
Contract – your personal information is processed in order to fulfil a contractual arrangement Consent – where you agree to us using your information in this way e.g. for storing your payment card details.
Legitimate Interests – this means the interests of us, in managing our business to allow us to provide you with the best products and service in the most secure and appropriate way e.g. to transfer your data to certain Third Party’s such as delivery partners.
Legal Obligation – where there is statutory or other legal requirement to share the information e.g. when we have to share your information for law enforcement purposes.
Here is a list of the ways that we may use your personal information, and which of the reasons described above we rely on to do so. Where we list legitimate interests as a reason, we also describe below what we believe these legitimate interests are.
What we use your personal information for
Our reasons (legal basis)
Our explanation of Associated Industries legitimate interests
Set up your Online log in
• Legitimate interest
Process efficiency in dealing with such activity.
Storing payment cards
• Consent
N/A
Process your orders
• Fulfilling a contract
N/A
Notify you of your order status.
• Legitimate interests
Process efficiency in dealing with such activity, and to make improvements to our services.
Manage your account/take payments/ provide customer services to you
• Legal obligation/ Legitimate interests (depending on nature of services)
Fulfilling a Contract
Keeping our records up to date, handling our customer contact efficiently and effectively, working out which of our products and services may interest you and telling you about them.
To detect, investigate and report financial crime (e.g. Fraud)
• Legal Obligation / legitimate interests
Developing and improving how we deal with financial crime. Complying with any legal obligation placed on us by regulators such as the FCA. Complying with any regulations that apply to us. Process efficiency in dealing with such activity, and to make service and process improvements.
Undertake website personalisation and administration.
• Legitimate interests
Developing products, services, applications and designs that attract and retain customers. Improving customer interaction with our sites. Defining types of customers for new products or services
Marketing communications to inform you of special offers, promotions, new lines and Sales. Provide you with online advertising.
• Legitimate interests
Developing products, services, applications and designs that attract and retain customers. Improving customer interaction with our sites.
Notifying you about enhancements to our services, such as changes to the website and new services that may be of interest to you.
• Legitimate interests
Developing products, services, applications and designs that attract and retain customers. Improving customer interaction with our sites.
Contact you to undertake customer satisfaction surveys, invite you to provide product reviews or for market research.
• Legitimate interests
Developing products, services, applications and designs that attract and retain customers. Improving customer interaction with our sites.
Maintaining network and data security
• Legitimate interests
To maintain the security of our network this in turns helps us to maintain the safety and confidentiality of your information.
Logistics planning, demand forecasting, management information and research
• Legitimate interests
We use information about shopping habits, products bought and volumes, to help us to respond to demand, ensure the right products get to the right areas and to help us plan our ranges.
Disclosure of your information, who we share it with and why
We work with a number of trusted suppliers, agencies and businesses in order to provide you the high quality goods and services you expect from us such as delivery companies, credit reference agencies, fraud prevention agencies, product technicians visiting your home or business address. Some may make use of cloud and/or hosted technologies. We undertake data security due diligence on our partners and ensure that that these partners conform to appropriate accreditations.
Some examples of the categories of third parties with whom we share your data are:
Suppliers & Partners
We works with a number of trusted partners who supply products and services on our behalf. All partners are subject to thorough security checks, and will only hold the minimum amount of personal information needed in order to fulfil the orders you place or provide a service on our behalf.
Delivery Partners In order for you to receive your goods, We work with a number of delivery partners. Again, we only pass limited information to them in order to ensure delivery of your items. IT Companies We work with businesses who support our website and other business systems. Payment processing We work with trusted third party payment processing providers in order to securely take and manage payments. Credit Reference Agencies
The identities of the CRAs, and the ways in which they use and share personal information, are explained in more detail at: Equifax Credit Reference Agency Information Notice
Other reasons may disclose your personal information to third parties:
In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms of Use or terms and conditions of supply and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Golf Direct, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
Where we store your personal data
Employees of Golf Direct Online Limited, engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transfers will be encrypted securely via one of the largest payment process providers.
Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.
Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site: any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try and prevent unauthorised access.
Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.
We may need your personal information to establish, bring or defend legal claims. For this purpose, we will always retain your personal information for 7 years after the date it is no longer needed by us for any of the purposes listed under How we use your information above. The only exceptions to this are where:
the law requires us to hold your personal information for a longer period, or delete it sooner;
you exercise your right to have the information erased (where it applies) and we do not need to hold it in connection with any of the reasons permitted or required under the law;
we bring or defend a legal claim or other proceedings during the period we retain your personal information, in which case we will retain your personal information until those proceedings have concluded and no further appeals are possible; or
in limited cases, existing or future law or a court or regulator requires us to keep your personal information for a longer or shorter period.
Data Protection Law
We operate under the Data Protection Act 2018 (‘DPA’) and the European General Data Protection Regulation (‘GDPR’).
The DPA and GDPR apply to ‘personal data’ we process and the data protection principles set out the main responsibilities we are responsible for.
We must ensure that personal data shall be:
Processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner
Collected for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes and not further processed in a manner that is incompatible with those purposes
Adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which they are processed
Accurate and where necessary kept up to date
Kept for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal data are processed. We operate a data retention policy that ensures we meet this obligation. We only retain personal data for the purposes for which it was collected and for a reasonable period thereafter where there is a legitimate business need or legal obligation to do so. For detail of our current retention policy contact our privacy officer at Sales@golf-direct.co.uk
Processed in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the personal data, including protection against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage, using appropriate technical or organisational measures.
We ensure lawful processing of personal data by obtaining consent; or where there is a contractual obligation to do so in providing appropriate products and services; or where processing the data is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests in providing appropriate products and services.
In the majority of cases we process personal data based on your contract with us. In other cases, we process personal data only where there are legitimate grounds for so doing.
To meet our Data Protection obligations, we have established comprehensive and proportionate governance measures.
We ensure data protection compliance across the organisation through:
Implementing appropriate technical and organisational measures including internal data protection policies, staff training, internal audits of processing activities, and reviews of internal HR policies
Maintaining relevant documentation on processing activities
Implementing measures that meet the principles of data protection by design and data protection by default including data minimisation, pseudonymisation, transparency, deploying the most up-to-date data security protocols and using data protection impact assessments across our organisation and in any third party arrangements
Under the GDPR You have the following specific rights in respect of the personal data we process:
Your rights
You are entitled to request the following from us, these are called your Data Subject Rights and there is more information on these on the Information Commissioners website www.ico.org.uk
Right of access –to request access to your personal information and information about how we process it
Right to rectification –to have your personal information corrected if it is inaccurate and to have incomplete personal information completed
Right to erasure (also known as the Right to be Forgotten) – to have your personal information erased. but only in very specific circumstances, typically where the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purpose for which it was originally collected
Right to restriction of processing – to restrict processing of your personal information
Right to data portability – to electronically move, copy or transfer your personal information in a standard form
Right to object – to object to processing of your personal information
Rights with regards to automated individual decision making, including profiling –rights relating to automated decision making, including profiling
You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at Sales@golf-direct.co.uk.
Please contact our privacy officer at Sales@golf-direct.co.uk for more information about the GDPR and your rights under Data Protection law.
If you have a complaint about data protection at Golf Direct, please contact our privacy officer at Sales@golf-direct.co.uk.
Alternatively contact our supervisory authority for data protection compliance: www.ico.org.uk:
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
SK9 5AF
Tel: 0303 123 1113 (local rate) or 01625 545 745 (national rate)
About cookies
Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can make the internet more useful by storing information about your preferences on a particular site, such as your personal preference pages.
The use of cookies is an industry standard, and most websites use them to provide useful features for their customers. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user’s computer. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies.
If you would prefer, you can set yours to refuse cookies. However, you may not be able to take full advantage of a website if you do so.
Changes to our privacy policy
Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.
Contact
Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to Sales@golf-direct.co.uk
Policy Last updated: 23/05/18
Leave a Reply Cancel replyYour email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *
Email *
Website
Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment.
Our Price Match Promise
Golf Direct will match the price of any other UK authorised online retailers.
We're always confident about our pricing, but if you find one of the competitors listed above has the same product cheaper please do give us a call on 0333 800 7272.
Find out more >
HELPFUL INFO.Golf Clothing Size Charts
Customer Reviews
Price Promise
GolfDirect Delivery and Returns Information
Golf Equipment Explained
SITE INFO.Contact
Blog
WHEN YOU ARE WANTING NEW GOLF EQUIPMENT, GOLF DEAL OR YOU'RE LOOKING FOR A GOLFING GIFT, THEN GOLF DIRECT HAS WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
Your Email (required)
Peace of mind at GolfDirect with SagePay and PayPal for secure payments
e-Commerce solutions by ACTISmedia
© 2020 Golf Direct
The number one online golf equipment store.
Search for:
Junior Golf Info.
Eyeline Golf (Practice Equipment)
Golf Mats (Practice Equipment)
Grip Trainers (Practice Equipment)
Swing Trainers (Practice Equipment)
Our Brands….
Our Brands….
Our Brands…..
Lost your password?
Register
Email address *
Password *
Register
